<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Jesus</title><description>telling the truth about Jesus</description><link>https://singular-niche.github.io</link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 1 Jun 2023 17:00:31 -0400</lastBuildDate><pubDate>Thu, 1 Jun 2023 17:00:31 -0400</pubDate><ttl>250</ttl><atom:link href="https://singular-niche.github.io/feed.rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><guid isPermaLink="true">https://singular-niche.github.io/posts/family</guid><title>would you like to belong to God's family?</title><description>the amazingly awesome good news about Jesus</description><link>https://singular-niche.github.io/posts/family</link><pubDate>Thu, 1 Jun 2023 16:42:00 -0400</pubDate><content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>would you like to belong to God's family?</h1><p><br> On earth we are born into a biological family -- we have a mom and dad and sometimes brothers and sisters, grandparents, uncles, aunts and cousins.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Jesus was born into a biological family, too. His mother Mary was a virgin when He was conceived through the Holy Spirit. His foster father was Joseph. He had brothers and sisters.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Luke 1:30-35,37 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>30 So the angel said to her, “Do not be afraid, Mary, for you have found favor with God!</p><p>31 Listen: You will become pregnant and give birth to a son, and you will name him Jesus.</p><p>32 He will be great, and will be called the Son of the Most High, and the Lord God will give him the throne of his father David.</p><p>33 He will reign over the house of Jacob forever, and his kingdom will never end.”</p><p>34 Mary said to the angel, “How will this be, since I have not been intimate with a man?”</p><p>35 The angel replied, “The Holy Spirit will come upon you, and the power of the Most High will overshadow you. Therefore the child to be born will be holy; he will be called the Son of God.</p><p>37 For nothing will be impossible with God.”</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 1:18-25 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>18 Now the birth of Jesus Christ happened this way. While his mother Mary was engaged to Joseph, but before they came together, she was found to be pregnant through the Holy Spirit.</p><p>19 Because Joseph, her husband to be, was a righteous man, and because he did not want to disgrace her, he intended to divorce her privately.</p><p>20 When he had contemplated this, an angel of the Lord appeared to him in a dream and said, “Joseph, son of David, do not be afraid to take Mary as your wife, because the child conceived in her is from the Holy Spirit.</p><p>21 She will give birth to a son and you will name him Jesus, because he will save his people from their sins.”</p><p>22 This all happened so that what was spoken by the Lord through the prophet would be fulfilled:</p><p>23 “Look! The virgin will conceive and give birth to a son, and they will name him Emmanuel,” which means “God with us.”</p><p>24 When Joseph awoke from sleep he did what the angel of the Lord told him. He took his wife,</p><p>25 but did not have marital relations with her until she gave birth to a son, whom he named Jesus.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 13:54-56 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>54 Then he came to his hometown and began to teach the people in their synagogue. They were astonished and said, “Where did this man get such wisdom and miraculous powers?</p><p>55 Isn’t this the carpenter’s son? Isn’t his mother named Mary? And aren’t his brothers James, Joseph, Simon, and Judas?</p><p>56 And aren’t all his sisters here with us? So where did he get all this?”</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Once when Jesus was young growing up in the small town of Nazareth, He gave His parents a fright on a trip to the city of Jerusalem.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Luke 2:41-52 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>41 Now Jesus’ parents went to Jerusalem every year for the Feast of the Passover.</p><p>42 When he was twelve years old, they went up according to custom.</p><p>43 But when the feast was over, as they were returning home, the boy Jesus stayed behind in Jerusalem. His parents did not know it,</p><p>44 but (because they assumed that he was in their group of travelers) they went a day’s journey. Then they began to look for him among their relatives and acquaintances.</p><p>45 When they did not find him, they returned to Jerusalem to look for him.</p><p>46 After three days they found him in the temple courts, sitting among the teachers, listening to them and asking them questions.</p><p>47 And all who heard Jesus were astonished at his understanding and his answers.</p><p>48 When his parents saw him, they were overwhelmed. His mother said to him, “Child, why have you treated us like this? Look, your father and I have been looking for you anxiously.”</p><p>49 But he replied, “Why were you looking for me? Didn’t you know that I must be in my Father’s house?”</p><p>50 Yet his parents did not understand the remark he made to them.</p><p>51 Then he went down with them and came to Nazareth, and was obedient to them. But his mother kept all these things in her heart.</p><p>52 And Jesus increased in wisdom and in stature, and in favor with God and with people.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Even when He was grown up, He respected His mother's wishes.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 2:1-12 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>1 Now on the third day there was a wedding at Cana in Galilee. Jesus’ mother was there,</p><p>2 and Jesus and his disciples were also invited to the wedding.</p><p>3 When the wine ran out, Jesus’ mother said to him, “They have no wine left.”</p><p>4 Jesus replied, “Woman, why are you saying this to me? My time has not yet come.”</p><p>5 His mother told the servants, “Whatever he tells you, do it.”</p><p>6 Now there were six stone water jars there for Jewish ceremonial washing, each holding twenty or thirty gallons.</p><p>7 Jesus told the servants, “Fill the water jars with water.” So they filled them up to the very top.</p><p>8 Then he told them, “Now draw some out and take it to the head steward,” and they did.</p><p>9 When the head steward tasted the water that had been turned to wine, not knowing where it came from (though the servants who had drawn the water knew), he called the bridegroom</p><p>10 and said to him, “Everyone serves the good wine first, and then the cheaper wine when the guests are drunk. You have kept the good wine until now!”</p><p>11 Jesus did this as the first of his miraculous signs, in Cana of Galilee. In this way he revealed his glory, and his disciples believed in him.</p><p>12 After this he went down to Capernaum with his mother and brothers and his disciples, and they stayed there a few days.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Jesus' biological family didn't always support Him.<br><br><br></p><h5><em>Mark 3:20-21 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>20 Now Jesus went home, and a crowd gathered so that they were not able to eat.</p><p>21 When his family heard this they went out to restrain him, for they said, “He is out of his mind.”</p><p><br><br> When they came to the house and called for Him to come out, He didn't go. Instead He explained to those listening who His true family is.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Mark 3:31-35 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>31 Then Jesus’ mother and his brothers came. Standing outside, they sent word to him, to summon him.</p><p>32 A crowd was sitting around him and they said to him, “Look, your mother and your brothers are outside looking for you.”</p><p>33 He answered them and said, “Who are my mother and my brothers?”</p><p>34 And looking at those who were sitting around him in a circle, he said, “Here are my mother and my brothers!</p><p>35 For whoever does the will of God is my brother and sister and mother.”</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Would you like to be part of Jesus's family?</p><p><br><br> You can!</p><p><br><br> Jesus is the Son of God. His family is God's family.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 6:28-29 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>28 So then they said to him, “What must we do to accomplish the deeds God requires?”</p><p>29 Jesus replied, “This is the deed God requires – to believe in the one whom he sent.”</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 1:12-13 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>12 But to all who have received him – those who believe in his name – he has given the right to become God’s children</p><p>13 – children not born by human parents or by human desire or a husband’s decision, but by God.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 3:3 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>3 Jesus replied, “I tell you the solemn truth, unless a person is born from above, he cannot see the kingdom of God.”</p><p><br><br> Jesus said:</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 6:37 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>37 “Everyone whom the Father gives me will come to me, and the one who comes to me I will never send away.”</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Why did God send His Son Jesus to earth?</p><p><br><br> Jesus said:</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Luke 19:10 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>10 “For the Son of Man came to seek and to save the lost.”</p><p><br> and</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Luke 5:32 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>32 “I have not come to call the righteous, but sinners to repentance.”</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> He told people to turn away from their sins, because God’s Kingdom was coming.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 4:17 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>17 From that time Jesus began to preach this message: “Repent, for the kingdom of heaven is near!”</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> He healed people from many diseases, did many miracles and taught people about the Kingdom of God.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 4:23-24 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>23 Jesus went throughout all of Galilee, teaching in their synagogues, preaching the gospel of the kingdom, and healing every kind of disease and sickness among the people.</p><p>24 So a report about him spread throughout Syria. People brought to him all who suffered with various illnesses and afflictions, those who had seizures, paralytics, and those possessed by demons, and he healed them.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> You can speak to Him in any language. He knows them all: He invented them.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Genesis 11:6-9 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>6 And the LORD said, “If as one people all sharing a common language they have begun to do this, then nothing they plan to do will be beyond them.</p><p>7 Come, let’s go down and confuse their language so they won’t be able to understand each other.”</p><p>8 So the LORD scattered them from there across the face of the entire earth, and they stopped building the city.</p><p>9 That is why its name was called Babel – because there the LORD confused the language of the entire world, and from there the LORD scattered them across the face of the entire earth.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> He can even hear your thoughts.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Mark 2:8 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>8 Now immediately, when Jesus realized in his spirit that they were contemplating such thoughts, he said to them, “Why are you thinking such things in your hearts?</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> We have all done bad things and aren’t good enough to come to God by ourselves.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>James 3:2 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>2 For we all stumble in many ways. If someone does not stumble in what he says, he is a perfect individual, able to control the entire body as well.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Isaiah 64:6 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>6 We are all like one who is unclean, all our so-called righteous acts are like a menstrual rag in your sight. We all wither like a leaf; our sins carry us away like the wind.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Psalms 14:1-2 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>1 Fools say to themselves, “There is no God.” They sin and commit evil deeds; none of them does what is right.</p><p>2 The LORD looks down from heaven at the human race, to see if there is anyone who is wise and seeks God.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Isaiah 53:6 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>6 All of us had wandered off like sheep; each of us had strayed off on his own path, but the LORD caused the sin of all of us to attack him.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> So Jesus took all the bad things on Himself and died to pay for them all, so that we could be forgiven.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>1 Peter 2:24 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>24 He himself bore our sins in his body on the tree, that we may cease from sinning and live for righteousness. By his wounds you were healed.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Isaiah 53:4-5 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>4 But he lifted up our illnesses, he carried our pain; even though we thought he was being punished, attacked by God, and afflicted for something he had done.</p><p>5 He was wounded because of our rebellious deeds, crushed because of our sins; he endured punishment that made us well; because of his wounds we have been healed.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Jesus told His disciples beforehand what would happen to Him in Jerusalem.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 16:21 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>21 From that time on Jesus began to show his disciples that he must go to Jerusalem and suffer many things at the hands of the elders, chief priests, and experts in the law, and be killed, and on the third day be raised.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 26:21-25 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>21 And while they were eating he said, “I tell you the truth, one of you will betray me.”</p><p>22 They became greatly distressed and each one began to say to him, “Surely not I, Lord?”</p><p>23 He answered, “The one who has dipped his hand into the bowl with me will betray me.</p><p>24 The Son of Man will go as it is written about him, but woe to that man by whom the Son of Man is betrayed! It would be better for him if he had never been born.”</p><p>25 Then Judas, the one who would betray him, said, “Surely not I, Rabbi?” Jesus replied, “You have said it yourself.”</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Mark 14:27-31 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>27 Then Jesus said to them, “You will all fall away, for it is written, ‘I will strike the shepherd, and the sheep will be scattered.’</p><p>28 But after I am raised, I will go ahead of you into Galilee.”</p><p>29 Peter said to him, “Even if they all fall away, I will not!”</p><p>30 Jesus said to him, “I tell you the truth, today – this very night – before a rooster crows twice, you will deny me three times.”</p><p>31 But Peter insisted emphatically, “Even if I must die with you, I will never deny you.” And all of them said the same thing.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Everything happened exactly as He said it would.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Luke 22:2-6 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>2 The chief priests and the experts in the law were trying to find some way to execute Jesus, for they were afraid of the people.</p><p>3 Then Satan entered Judas, the one called Iscariot, who was one of the twelve.</p><p>4 He went away and discussed with the chief priests and officers of the temple guard how he might betray Jesus, handing him over to them.</p><p>5 They were delighted and arranged to give him money.</p><p>6 So Judas agreed and began looking for an opportunity to betray Jesus when no crowd was present.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 18:3-12 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>3 So Judas obtained a squad of soldiers and some officers of the chief priests and Pharisees. They came to the orchard with lanterns and torches and weapons.</p><p>4 Then Jesus, because he knew everything that was going to happen to him, came and asked them, “Who are you looking for?”</p><p>5 They replied, “Jesus the Nazarene.” He told them, “I am he.” (Now Judas, the one who betrayed him, was standing there with them.)</p><p>6 So when Jesus said to them, “I am he,” they retreated and fell to the ground.</p><p>7 Then Jesus asked them again, “Who are you looking for?” And they said, “Jesus the Nazarene.”</p><p>8 Jesus replied, “I told you that I am he. If you are looking for me, let these men go.”</p><p>9 He said this to fulfill the word he had spoken, “I have not lost a single one of those whom you gave me.”</p><p>10 Then Simon Peter, who had a sword, pulled it out and struck the high priest’s slave, cutting off his right ear. (Now the slave’s name was Malchus.)</p><p>11 But Jesus said to Peter, “Put your sword back into its sheath! Am I not to drink the cup that the Father has given me?”</p><p>12 Then the squad of soldiers with their commanding officer and the officers of the Jewish leaders arrested Jesus and tied him up.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Mark 14:53-72 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>53 Then they led Jesus to the high priest, and all the chief priests and elders and experts in the law came together.</p><p>54 And Peter had followed him from a distance, up to the high priest’s courtyard. He was sitting with the guards and warming himself by the fire.</p><p>55 The chief priests and the whole Sanhedrin were looking for evidence against Jesus so that they could put him to death, but they did not find anything.</p><p>56 Many gave false testimony against him, but their testimony did not agree.</p><p>57 Some stood up and gave this false testimony against him:</p><p>58 “We heard him say, ‘I will destroy this temple made with hands and in three days build another not made with hands.’”</p><p>59 Yet even on this point their testimony did not agree.</p><p>60 Then the high priest stood up before them and asked Jesus, “Have you no answer? What is this that they are testifying against you?”</p><p>61 But he was silent and did not answer. Again the high priest questioned him, “Are you the Christ, the Son of the Blessed One?”</p><p>62 “I am,” said Jesus, “and you will see the Son of Man sitting at the right hand of the Power and coming with the clouds of heaven.”</p><p>63 Then the high priest tore his clothes and said, “Why do we still need witnesses?</p><p>64 You have heard the blasphemy! What is your verdict?” They all condemned him as deserving death.</p><p>65 Then some began to spit on him, and to blindfold him, and to strike him with their fists, saying, “Prophesy!” The guards also took him and beat him.</p><p>66 Now while Peter was below in the courtyard, one of the high priest’s slave girls came by.</p><p>67 When she saw Peter warming himself, she looked directly at him and said, “You also were with that Nazarene, Jesus.”</p><p>68 But he denied it: “I don’t even understand what you’re talking about!” Then he went out to the gateway, and a rooster crowed.</p><p>69 When the slave girl saw him, she began again to say to the bystanders, “This man is one of them.”</p><p>70 But he denied it again. A short time later the bystanders again said to Peter, “You must be one of them, because you are also a Galilean.”</p><p>71 Then he began to curse, and he swore with an oath, “I do not know this man you are talking about!”</p><p>72 Immediately a rooster crowed a second time. Then Peter remembered what Jesus had said to him: “Before a rooster crows twice, you will deny me three times.” And he broke down and wept.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Acts 2:22-24 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>22 “Men of Israel, listen to these words: Jesus the Nazarene, a man clearly attested to you by God with powerful deeds, wonders, and miraculous signs that God performed among you through him, just as you yourselves know –</p><p>23 this man, who was handed over by the predetermined plan and foreknowledge of God, you executed by nailing him to a cross at the hands of Gentiles.</p><p>24 But God raised him up, having released him from the pains of death, because it was not possible for him to be held in its power.”</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 20:1-18 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>1 Now very early on the first day of the week, while it was still dark, Mary Magdalene came to the tomb and saw that the stone had been moved away from the entrance.</p><p>2 So she went running to Simon Peter and the other disciple whom Jesus loved and told them, “They have taken the Lord from the tomb, and we don’t know where they have put him!”</p><p>3 Then Peter and the other disciple set out to go to the tomb.</p><p>4 The two were running together, but the other disciple ran faster than Peter and reached the tomb first.</p><p>5 He bent down and saw the strips of linen cloth lying there, but he did not go in.</p><p>6 Then Simon Peter, who had been following him, arrived and went right into the tomb. He saw the strips of linen cloth lying there,</p><p>7 and the face cloth, which had been around Jesus’ head, not lying with the strips of linen cloth but rolled up in a place by itself.</p><p>8 Then the other disciple, who had reached the tomb first, came in, and he saw and believed.</p><p>9 (For they did not yet understand the scripture that Jesus must rise from the dead.)</p><p>10 So the disciples went back to their homes.</p><p>11 But Mary stood outside the tomb weeping. As she wept, she bent down and looked into the tomb.</p><p>12 And she saw two angels in white sitting where Jesus’ body had been lying, one at the head and one at the feet.</p><p>13 They said to her, “Woman, why are you weeping?” Mary replied, “They have taken my Lord away, and I do not know where they have put him!”</p><p>14 When she had said this, she turned around and saw Jesus standing there, but she did not know that it was Jesus.</p><p>15 Jesus said to her, “Woman, why are you weeping? Who are you looking for?” Because she thought he was the gardener, she said to him, “Sir, if you have carried him away, tell me where you have put him, and I will take him.”</p><p>16 Jesus said to her, “Mary.” She turned and said to him in Aramaic, “Rabboni” (which means Teacher).</p><p>17 Jesus replied, “Do not touch me, for I have not yet ascended to my Father. Go to my brothers and tell them, ‘I am ascending to my Father and your Father, to my God and your God.’”</p><p>18 Mary Magdalene came and informed the disciples, “I have seen the Lord!” And she told them what Jesus had said to her.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> He was seen alive by many of His disciples and then was taken up into Heaven.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>1 Corinthians 15:3-8 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>3 For I passed on to you as of first importance what I also received – that Christ died for our sins according to the scriptures,</p><p>4 and that he was buried, and that he was raised on the third day according to the scriptures,</p><p>5 and that he appeared to Cephas, then to the twelve.</p><p>6 Then he appeared to more than five hundred of the brothers and sisters at one time, most of whom are still alive, though some have fallen asleep.</p><p>7 Then he appeared to James, then to all the apostles.</p><p>8 Last of all, as though to one born at the wrong time, he appeared to me also.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Acts 1:6-11 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>6 So when they had gathered together, they began to ask him, “Lord, is this the time when you are restoring the kingdom to Israel?”</p><p>7 He told them, “You are not permitted to know the times or periods that the Father has set by his own authority.</p><p>8 But you will receive power when the Holy Spirit has come upon you, and you will be my witnesses in Jerusalem, and in all Judea and Samaria, and to the farthest parts of the earth.”</p><p>9 After he had said this, while they were watching, he was lifted up and a cloud hid him from their sight.</p><p>10 As they were still staring into the sky while he was going, suddenly two men in white clothing stood near them</p><p>11 and said, “Men of Galilee, why do you stand here looking up into the sky? This same Jesus who has been taken up from you into heaven will come back in the same way you saw him go into heaven.”</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> We need to believe in Him, turn away from sin, and receive Him into our hearts. Then we can be born again spiritually into God’s family.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 1:12-13 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>12 But to all who have received him – those who believe in his name – he has given the right to become God’s children</p><p>13 – children not born by human parents or by human desire or a husband’s decision, but by God.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 5:14 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>14 After this Jesus found him at the temple and said to him, “Look, you have become well. Don’t sin any more, lest anything worse happen to you.”</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Whenever we sin, we must be open and honest with Jesus and confess our sin to Him and receive His forgiveness.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>1 John 1:6-10 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>6 If we say we have fellowship with him and yet keep on walking in the darkness, we are lying and not practicing the truth.</p><p>7 But if we walk in the light as he himself is in the light, we have fellowship with one another and the blood of Jesus his Son cleanses us from all sin.</p><p>8 If we say we do not bear the guilt of sin, we are deceiving ourselves and the truth is not in us.</p><p>9 But if we confess our sins, he is faithful and righteous, forgiving us our sins and cleansing us from all unrighteousness.</p><p>10 If we say we have not sinned, we make him a liar and his word is not in us.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Following Jesus isn’t easy, but it’s worth it.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 22:37-40 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>37 Jesus said to him, “‘Love the Lord your God with all your heart, with all your soul, and with all your mind.’</p><p>38 This is the first and greatest commandment.</p><p>39 The second is like it: ‘Love your neighbor as yourself.’</p><p>40 All the law and the prophets depend on these two commandments.”</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 7:12-14 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>12 In everything, treat others as you would want them to treat you, for this fulfills the law and the prophets.</p><p>13 “Enter through the narrow gate, because the gate is wide and the way is spacious that leads to destruction, and there are many who enter through it.</p><p>14 How narrow is the gate and difficult the way that leads to life, and there are few who find it!</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 16:24-27 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>24 Then Jesus said to his disciples, “If anyone wants to become my follower, he must deny himself, take up his cross, and follow me.</p><p>25 For whoever wants to save his life will lose it, but whoever loses his life because of me will find it.</p><p>26 For what does it benefit a person if he gains the whole world but forfeits his life? Or what can a person give in exchange for his life?</p><p>27 For the Son of Man will come with his angels in the glory of his Father, and then he will reward each person according to what he has done.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> One day Jesus will come back suddenly -- when no one is expecting Him.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 24:36-44 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>36 “But as for that day and hour no one knows it – not even the angels in heaven – except the Father alone.</p><p>37 For just like the days of Noah were, so the coming of the Son of Man will be.</p><p>38 For in those days before the flood, people were eating and drinking, marrying and giving in marriage, until the day Noah entered the ark.</p><p>39 And they knew nothing until the flood came and took them all away. It will be the same at the coming of the Son of Man.</p><p>40 Then there will be two men in the field; one will be taken and one left.</p><p>41 There will be two women grinding grain with a mill; one will be taken and one left.</p><p>42 “Therefore stay alert, because you do not know on what day your Lord will come.</p><p>43 But understand this: If the owner of the house had known at what time of night the thief was coming, he would have been alert and would not have let his house be broken into.</p><p>44 Therefore you also must be ready, because the Son of Man will come at an hour when you do not expect him.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Everyone on earth will see Him; it will not be a secret.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 24:23-27 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>23 Then if anyone says to you, ‘Look, here is the Christ!’ or ‘There he is!’ do not believe him.</p><p>24 For false messiahs and false prophets will appear and perform great signs and wonders to deceive, if possible, even the elect.</p><p>25 Remember, I have told you ahead of time.</p><p>26 So then, if someone says to you, ‘Look, he is in the wilderness,’ do not go out, or ‘Look, he is in the inner rooms,’ do not believe him.</p><p>27 For just like the lightning comes from the east and flashes to the west, so the coming of the Son of Man will be.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> He will gather all those who belong to Him and take us home.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 24:29-31 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>29 “Immediately after the suffering of those days, the sun will be darkened, and the moon will not give its light; the stars will fall from heaven, and the powers of heaven will be shaken.</p><p>30 Then the sign of the Son of Man will appear in heaven, and all the tribes of the earth will mourn. They will see the Son of Man arriving on the clouds of heaven with power and great glory.</p><p>31 And he will send his angels with a loud trumpet blast, and they will gather his elect from the four winds, from one end of heaven to the other.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> He warned us that before He comes back there would be many false prophets, false teachers and false Messiahs who would claim to be His followers but then try to lead us astray.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 24:4-5 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>4 Jesus answered them, “Watch out that no one misleads you.</p><p>5 For many will come in my name, saying, ‘I am the Christ,’ and they will mislead many.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 24:11-13 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>11 And many false prophets will appear and deceive many,</p><p>12 and because lawlessness will increase so much, the love of many will grow cold.</p><p>13 But the person who endures to the end will be saved.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>2 Thessalonians 2:8-12 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>8 and then the lawless one will be revealed, whom the Lord will destroy by the breath of his mouth and wipe out by the manifestation of his arrival.</p><p>9 The arrival of the lawless one will be by Satan’s working with all kinds of miracles and signs and false wonders,</p><p>10 and with every kind of evil deception directed against those who are perishing, because they found no place in their hearts for the truth so as to be saved.</p><p>11 Consequently God sends on them a deluding influence so that they will believe what is false.</p><p>12 And so all of them who have not believed the truth but have delighted in evil will be condemned.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> He explained to us beforehand how we could recognize them and avoid being deceived.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 7:15-20 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>15 “Watch out for false prophets, who come to you in sheep’s clothing but inwardly are voracious wolves.</p><p>16 You will recognize them by their fruit. Grapes are not gathered from thorns or figs from thistles, are they?</p><p>17 In the same way, every good tree bears good fruit, but the bad tree bears bad fruit.</p><p>18 A good tree is not able to bear bad fruit, nor a bad tree to bear good fruit.</p><p>19 Every tree that does not bear good fruit is cut down and thrown into the fire.</p><p>20 So then, you will recognize them by their fruit.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>John 8:31-32 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>31 Then Jesus said to those Judeans who had believed him, “If you continue to follow my teaching, you are really my disciples</p><p>32 and you will know the truth, and the truth will set you free.”</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> There are still many who don't know the truth.</p><p><br> God wants to rescue everyone who is willing.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>2 Peter 3:3-9 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>3 Above all, understand this: In the last days blatant scoffers will come, being propelled by their own evil urges</p><p>4 and saying, “Where is his promised return? For ever since our ancestors died, all things have continued as they were from the beginning of creation.”</p><p>5 For they deliberately suppress this fact, that by the word of God heavens existed long ago and an earth was formed out of water and by means of water.</p><p>6 Through these things the world existing at that time was destroyed when it was deluged with water.</p><p>7 But by the same word the present heavens and earth have been reserved for fire, by being kept for the day of judgment and destruction of the ungodly.</p><p>8 Now, dear friends, do not let this one thing escape your notice, that a single day is like a thousand years with the Lord and a thousand years are like a single day.</p><p>9 The Lord is not slow concerning his promise, as some regard slowness, but is being patient toward you, because he does not wish for any to perish but for all to come to repentance.</p><p><br></p><center>✝️</center><p><br><br> Jesus commanded us to tell others the Good News, to baptize those who believe, and help them to follow Him.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Mark 16:15-20 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>15 He said to them, “Go into all the world and preach the gospel to every creature.</p><p>16 The one who believes and is baptized will be saved, but the one who does not believe will be condemned.</p><p>17 These signs will accompany those who believe: In my name they will drive out demons; they will speak in new languages;</p><p>18 they will pick up snakes with their hands, and whatever poison they drink will not harm them; they will place their hands on the sick and they will be well.”</p><p>19 After the Lord Jesus had spoken to them, he was taken up into heaven and sat down at the right hand of God.</p><p>20 They went out and proclaimed everywhere, while the Lord worked with them and confirmed the word through the accompanying signs.</p><p><br></p><h5><em>Matthew 28:18-20 (NET)</em></h5><h6><br></h6><p>18 Then Jesus came up and said to them, “All authority in heaven and on earth has been given to me.</p><p>19 Therefore go and make disciples of all nations, baptizing them in the name of the Father and the Son and the Holy Spirit,</p><p>20 teaching them to obey everything I have commanded you. And remember, I am with you always, to the end of the age.”</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>